<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome to the SPiN-LAB on My New Hugo Site</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome to the SPiN-LAB on My New Hugo Site</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://spinlab-uom.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/about/</guid><description>Left to right: Varun, Georgia, Caroline, Anna, and Shruti. We will need a new team photo as the lab has already grown since this was taken!
We are a research group based at the Univerity of Manchester interested in mechanisms of brain plasticity during neurodevelopment. We use a combination of advanced brain imaging and computational methods to understand how brain plasticity is altered in certain genetic conditions and how that affects learning.</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/publications/</guid><description>2023 Beyond global synchrony: equivalence between Kuramoto oscillators and Wilson-Cowan model for large-scale brain networks Abd-Elrazik AH, Torres FA, Otero M, Lea-Carnall CA, El-Deredy W. Proceedings Volume 12567, 18th International Symposium on Medical Information Processing and Analysis; 125671B (2023).
Aberrant oscillatory activity in neurofibromatosis type 1: an EEG study of resting state and working memory Booth SJ, Garg S, Brown LJE, Green J, Pobric G, Taylor JR. A. J Neurodev Disord.</description></item><item><title>Lab Manual</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/lab-manual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/lab-manual/</guid><description>Introduction Hello and welcome to the SPiN Lab! This manual lays out how the lab works, and the expectations of everyone within it
Roles and Responsibilities PIs
will have a vision for the lab and be aware of current research in our area
will be actively submitting funding applications to support the science in the lab
will support you in your career development
will dedicate time to meeting with you to help you progress your science</description></item><item><title>MRI Preparation</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/mri-preparation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/mri-preparation/</guid><description>Enim consequat sunt esse fugiat fugiat fugiat sint adipisicing ex ullamco dolor cupidatat quis. Cillum tempor labore laboris cillum aliquip incididunt velit elit deserunt. Aute nulla ex laboris proident et reprehenderit officia quis elit nisi Lorem. Consectetur sit magna duis ullamco aliquip incididunt nostrud elit est consequat sunt sit.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/contact/</guid><description>This is an example of a custom shortcode that you can put right into your content. You will need to add a form action to the the shortcode to make it work. Check out Formspree for a simple, free form service.
Your Name Email Address An email address is required. Message</description></item><item><title>New paper: Temporal trends in eating disorder and self-harm incidence rates among adolescents and young adults in the UK</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/news/news-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/news/news-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>In our latest paper we examine the incidence rates of these psychopathologies among young people in the UK in the 2 years following onset of the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fully funded EPSRC-DTP</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/news/news-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/news/news-2/</guid><description>We are recruting!
Exploring how eye movements and pupil response during learning relate to neurotransmission: A combined neuroimaging and eye tracking study
About the Project Glutamate and GABA are two important neurotransmitters in the brain. Glutamate is the main excitatory neurotransmitter, while GABA is the main inhibitory neurotransmitter. Glutamate and GABA work together to maintain a balance between excitation and inhibition in the brain, which is essential for normal cognitive function.</description></item><item><title>New Paper: A Targeted, Low-Throughput Compound Screen in a Drosophila Model of Neurofibromatosis Type 1 Identifies Simvastatin and BMS-204352 as Potential Therapies for Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD)</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/news/news-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/news/news-3/</guid><description>Check out our latest paper:
A Targeted, Low-Throughput Compound Screen in a Drosophila Model of Neurofibromatosis Type 1 Identifies Simvastatin and BMS-204352 as Potential Therapies for Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) Dyson A, Ryan M, Garg S, Evans DG, Baines RA. eNeuro, DOI: 10.1523/ENEURO.0461-22.2023</description></item><item><title>New Paper: Noise-modulated multistable synapses in a Wilson-Cowan-based model of plasticity</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/news/news-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/news/news-4/</guid><description>In our latest computational paper we investigate plasticity dynamics in a WC-based model of interacting neural populations coupled with activity-dependent synapses in which a periodic stimulation was applied in the presence of noise of controlled intensity. We found that for a narrow range of the noise variance, synaptic strength can be optimized. In particular, there is a regime of noise intensity for which synaptic strength presents a triple-stable state. Regulating noise intensity affects the probability that the system chooses one of the stable states, thereby controlling plasticity.</description></item><item><title>New Paper: A mean-field model of glutamate and GABA synaptic dynamics for functional MRS</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/news/news-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/news/news-5/</guid><description>In our latest paper we test the hypothesis that fMRS detects shifts in metabolite concentrations as they move from presynaptic vesicles, where they are largely invisible to MRS, to extracellular and cytosolic pools, where they are visible to MRS using a mean field model which links the neural dynamics of neurotransmitters at the microscopic-level to the macroscopic-level imaging measurements obtained in experimental studies.
A mean-field model of glutamate and GABA synaptic dynamics for functional MRS Lea-Carnall CA, El-Deredy W, Stagg CJ, Williams SR, Trujillo-Barreto NJ, NeuroImage, DOI: 10.</description></item><item><title>To-do list</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/news/news-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/news/news-6/</guid><description>Things to do
Logo low res - tried to update?
Logo SPiN? -done but not updaed?
Pictures not same size for people
News on front page (done?)
Add a team pic to the About page (coming)</description></item><item><title>Amir Abbas Khanbeigi</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/abbas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/abbas/</guid><description>Labore duis aute ex id voluptate irure duis esse. Consequat voluptate commodo reprehenderit mollit officia mollit nulla proident esse proident voluptate ad magna. Nisi magna do aliquip cupidatat consectetur fugiat in magna. Exercitation mollit aliqua labore est nisi dolore. Pariatur reprehenderit in aute exercitation Lorem esse incididunt exercitation fugiat sunt proident quis. Eu ipsum quis elit voluptate labore voluptate voluptate consequat ea exercitation reprehenderit sit. Veniam amet Lorem aute quis.</description></item><item><title>Anna Wild</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/anna/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/anna/</guid><description>Labore duis aute ex id voluptate irure duis esse. Consequat voluptate commodo reprehenderit mollit officia mollit nulla proident esse proident voluptate ad magna. Nisi magna do aliquip cupidatat consectetur fugiat in magna. Exercitation mollit aliqua labore est nisi dolore. Pariatur reprehenderit in aute exercitation Lorem esse incididunt exercitation fugiat sunt proident quis. Eu ipsum quis elit voluptate labore voluptate voluptate consequat ea exercitation reprehenderit sit. Veniam amet Lorem aute quis.</description></item><item><title>Caroline Lea-Carnall</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/caroline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/caroline/</guid><description>Labore duis aute ex id voluptate irure duis esse. Consequat voluptate commodo reprehenderit mollit officia mollit nulla proident esse proident voluptate ad magna. Nisi magna do aliquip cupidatat consectetur fugiat in magna. Exercitation mollit aliqua labore est nisi dolore. Pariatur reprehenderit in aute exercitation Lorem esse incididunt exercitation fugiat sunt proident quis. Eu ipsum quis elit voluptate labore voluptate voluptate consequat ea exercitation reprehenderit sit. Veniam amet Lorem aute quis.</description></item><item><title>Marta Czime Litwińczuk</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/czime/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/czime/</guid><description>I have joined the Spin-Lab in September 2023 as a Postdoctoral Research Associate in Neuroimaging and Computational Modelling. I have a background in undergraduate Psychology, where I developed an interest in neural basis of executive function, language, perception and wellbeing. I pursued my interests further with a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Neuroimaging for Clinical and Cognitive Neuroscience and followed by pursuit of a Ph.D. in Cognitive Neuroscience. During my Ph.D. I investigated how the relationship between structural and functional connectivity of the brain contributes to modelling of cognition.</description></item><item><title>Shruti Garg</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/shruti/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/shruti/</guid><description>I did my general medical training at Grant Medical College, Mumbai India beofre training in general psychiatry at Oxford &amp;amp; Leeds. I moved to Manchester in 2008 to specialise in Child &amp;amp; Adolescent Psychiatry. I was awarded a research training fellowship by NIHR Bioedical Research centre in 2011-12 to study the behavioural phenotype of Neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF1). My PhD thesis described for the first time, a high prevalence of Autism Spectrum Disorders (ASD) in NF1.</description></item><item><title>Varun Chandran</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/varun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/varun/</guid><description>Varun Arunachalam Chandran, PhD
Postdoctoral Research Associate- Faculty of biology, medicine and health, University of Manchester
Email: varun.chandran@manchester.ac.uk
Currently, I work as a postdoctoral research associate for a study titled ‘Neuroimaging in Rasopathies’ (funded by NIHR-BRC) at the faculty of biology, medicine and health, University of Manchester, United Kingdom. In the current research project, we examine the inhibitory/excitatory imbalance associated with GABA/glutamate, functional connectivity and myelin differences underpinning learning and working memory difficulties in children with Rasopathies specifically including Neurofibromatosis type-I and Noonan Syndrome as well as its phenotypic relationship with Autism Spectrum Conditions (ASC).</description></item></channel></rss>