<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>People on SPiN-LAB Studying Plasticity in Neurodevelopment</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/</link><description>Recent content in People on SPiN-LAB Studying Plasticity in Neurodevelopment</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Caroline Lea-Carnall</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/caroline/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/caroline/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>I am a theoretical neuroscientist with a specific interest in the neurochemical mechanisms that underlie plasticity. I use a combination of computational and neuroimaging methods to study plasticity in humans in vivo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shruti Garg</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/shruti/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/shruti/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>I did my general medical training at Grant Medical College, Mumbai India beofre training in general psychiatry at Oxford &amp;amp; Leeds. I moved to Manchester in 2008 to specialise in Child &amp;amp; Adolescent Psychiatry. I was awarded a research training fellowship by NIHR Bioedical Research centre in 2011-12 to study the behavioural phenotype of Neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF1). My PhD thesis described for the first time, a high prevalence of Autism Spectrum Disorders (ASD) in NF1. This work has formed the basis for my research programme in NF1 autism. In August 2018 I was awarded the Francis Collins Scholarship in NF1 by NTAP (Neurofibromatosis Therapeutics Acceleration Program), at John&amp;rsquo;s Hopkins University (&lt;a href="http://www.n-tap.org/new-research-tools-for-neurofibromatosis-type-1-2-2-2/)">http://www.n-tap.org/new-research-tools-for-neurofibromatosis-type-1-2-2-2/)&lt;/a>. This work will allow me to investigate the use of non-invasive brain stimulation for working memory deficits in NF1.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Amir Abbas Khanbeigi</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/abbas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/abbas/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>I am a PhD student in computational neuroscience with a background in engineering and theoretical physics. My research includes providing mathematical framework to optimise the parameters of non-invasive brain stimulations with the purpose of improving Working Memory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More specifically, I am interested in bridging between empirical data and computational models of large-scale brain networks by drawing implications from latent manifold of neuroimaging data. With insights from dynamical systems and complex system physics, I seek to put constraints on computational models of brain networks using the embedding and intrinsic dimension of Working Memory manifold.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Anna Wild</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/anna/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/anna/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>I studied an integrated Masters in Cognitive Neuroscience and Psychology at the University of Manchester from 2019 until 2023. Here, I developed an interest in neuroimaging and undertook MRI and fMRI analysis projects in my 3rd and 4th year. This included my yearlong master’s project, employing fMRI analysis to examine negativity biases in depression when listening to music. Currently, I am working as a PhD student in the SpiN-LAB.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gamze Kaplan</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/gamze/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/gamze/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Gamze Kaplan, MA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Postgraduate Researcher - Faculty of Biology, Medicine and Health, University of Manchester&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After completing my undergraduate degree in Special Education, I pursued a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Early Childhood Education at Anglia Ruskin University. During my time there, I conducted research on the experiences of first-generation immigrant parents while accessing early intervention services for their children with disabilities. Currently, I am a PhD researcher in the Division of Psychology at the University of Manchester. My project focuses on studying the psychological impact of NF1 on both children and parents. Specifically, I am exploring how expectant parents with NF1 experience pregnancy, and the parent-infant interaction patterns of infants with NF1 and familial ADHD likelihood.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jessica Ward</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/jess/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/jess/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Jess is a Research Assistant with a background in Psychology. Jess holds a BSc(Hons) in Psychology from Lancaster University and an MSc in Clinical and Health Psychology from the University of Manchester. Jess has worked for the NHS within a learning disability and dementia service, and most recently worked as a Research Officer in Australia for the University of New South Wales. Jess is passionate about patient and public involvement and has extensive experience supporting people with lived experience to be involved and engaged in all stages of the research cycle. Through her research, Jess has been involved in developing a new model of preventive care for people with learning disabilities in Australia. Outside of work, Jess loves to read fiction, cook and try out new recipes, practice Pilates, and watch films.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Marta Litwińczuk</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/czime/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/czime/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>I have joined the Spin-Lab in September 2023 as a Postdoctoral Research Associate in Neuroimaging and Computational Modelling. I have a background in undergraduate Psychology, where I developed an interest in neural basis of executive function, language, perception and wellbeing. I pursued my interests further with a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Neuroimaging for Clinical and Cognitive Neuroscience and followed by pursuit of a Ph.D. in Cognitive Neuroscience. During my Ph.D. I investigated how the relationship between structural and functional connectivity of the brain contributes to modelling of cognition. My current research focuses on modelling effects of non-invasive brain stimulation on functional connectivity during working memory in neurofirbromatosis type 1 (NF1) and neurotypical controls.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Matthew Mccowen</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/matthew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/matthew/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>During my undergraduate studies in Psychology and my master&amp;rsquo;s in Neuroimaging for Clinical and Cognitive Neuroscience, I developed a strong interest in the neural mechanisms of memory. Currently, as an MRC-DTP PhD student, I am investigating the relationship between pupillary response, brain activation, and concentrations of GABA and glutamate during learning and memory processes in individuals with neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF1) as well as neurotypical controls. T&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paola Martinez</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/paola/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/paola/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>I am a BSc Neuroscience student completing an Industrial Placement at the SPIN lab. My primary research project is titled ‘Comparing BOLD fMRI activation in the Dorsal Attention Network (DAN), Default Mode Network (DMN) and Fronto-Parietal Control Network (FPCN) in NF1 patients and controls, during a Verbal Working Memory Task’. Through this project I gained experience in cognitive data collection, data analysis, data management, project management and have obtained experience using MATLAB’s SPM for fMRI analysis. My current supervisors are Dr Marta Czime Litwińczuk and Dr Shruti Garg.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sadali Wanniarachchi</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/sadali/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/sadali/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>I am an MRC-DTP student studying a PhD in cognitive neuroscience under the supervision of Dr Shruti Garg and Professor Jonathan Green. I completed my undergraduate degree in Applied Medical Sciences at University College London following which I did a Master of Research in neuroscience at the University of St Andrews. During my masters, I investigated the impact of optogenetic neuromodulation on locomotion in Drosophila Melanogaster larvae which prompted my interest in motor function. I am currently investigating early neurophysiological and motor markers of ADHD traits in NF1.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tom Wright</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/tom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/tom/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>I graduated with an MBChB(Hons) from the University of Liverpool in 2013 and gained MRCP(UK) in 2017. I completed the UK foundation programme and core medical training in Merseyside and South Yorkshire, respectively. Following on from this, I undertook an MSc in Human and Molecular Genetics at the University of Sheffield and began higher specialty training in Clinical Genetics in 2020. I have temporarily paused this role to undertake a Clinical Doctoral Fellowship funded by the NIHR Manchester Biomedical Research Centre (BRC), under the primary supervision of Dr Shruti Garg.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Varun Chandran</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/varun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/varun/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Varun Arunachalam Chandran, PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Postdoctoral Research Associate- Faculty of biology, medicine and health, University of Manchester&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I completed my doctoral study in Neurosciences at the University of Reading. My doctoral research was aimed to investigate the neural correlates of autistic traits across the clinical and non-clinical population using a dimensional approach. To address this, I used multimodal brain imaging techniques including Diffusion Tensor Imaging, Structural MRI, and resting-state functional MRI to examine the white matter microstructure, grey matter (cortical volume, thickness, surface area and gyrification), and intrinsic functional connectivity (resting state networks).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>