<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>People on My New Hugo Site</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/</link><description>Recent content in People on My New Hugo Site</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Amir Abbas Khanbeigi</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/abbas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/abbas/</guid><description>Labore duis aute ex id voluptate irure duis esse. Consequat voluptate commodo reprehenderit mollit officia mollit nulla proident esse proident voluptate ad magna. Nisi magna do aliquip cupidatat consectetur fugiat in magna. Exercitation mollit aliqua labore est nisi dolore. Pariatur reprehenderit in aute exercitation Lorem esse incididunt exercitation fugiat sunt proident quis. Eu ipsum quis elit voluptate labore voluptate voluptate consequat ea exercitation reprehenderit sit. Veniam amet Lorem aute quis.</description></item><item><title>Anna Wild</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/anna/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/anna/</guid><description>Labore duis aute ex id voluptate irure duis esse. Consequat voluptate commodo reprehenderit mollit officia mollit nulla proident esse proident voluptate ad magna. Nisi magna do aliquip cupidatat consectetur fugiat in magna. Exercitation mollit aliqua labore est nisi dolore. Pariatur reprehenderit in aute exercitation Lorem esse incididunt exercitation fugiat sunt proident quis. Eu ipsum quis elit voluptate labore voluptate voluptate consequat ea exercitation reprehenderit sit. Veniam amet Lorem aute quis.</description></item><item><title>Caroline Lea-Carnall</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/caroline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/caroline/</guid><description>Labore duis aute ex id voluptate irure duis esse. Consequat voluptate commodo reprehenderit mollit officia mollit nulla proident esse proident voluptate ad magna. Nisi magna do aliquip cupidatat consectetur fugiat in magna. Exercitation mollit aliqua labore est nisi dolore. Pariatur reprehenderit in aute exercitation Lorem esse incididunt exercitation fugiat sunt proident quis. Eu ipsum quis elit voluptate labore voluptate voluptate consequat ea exercitation reprehenderit sit. Veniam amet Lorem aute quis.</description></item><item><title>Marta Czime Litwińczuk</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/czime/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/czime/</guid><description>I have joined the Spin-Lab in September 2023 as a Postdoctoral Research Associate in Neuroimaging and Computational Modelling. I have a background in undergraduate Psychology, where I developed an interest in neural basis of executive function, language, perception and wellbeing. I pursued my interests further with a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Neuroimaging for Clinical and Cognitive Neuroscience and followed by pursuit of a Ph.D. in Cognitive Neuroscience. During my Ph.D. I investigated how the relationship between structural and functional connectivity of the brain contributes to modelling of cognition.</description></item><item><title>Shruti Garg</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/shruti/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/shruti/</guid><description>I did my general medical training at Grant Medical College, Mumbai India beofre training in general psychiatry at Oxford &amp;amp; Leeds. I moved to Manchester in 2008 to specialise in Child &amp;amp; Adolescent Psychiatry. I was awarded a research training fellowship by NIHR Bioedical Research centre in 2011-12 to study the behavioural phenotype of Neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF1). My PhD thesis described for the first time, a high prevalence of Autism Spectrum Disorders (ASD) in NF1.</description></item><item><title>Varun Chandran</title><link>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/varun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spinlab-uom.github.io/people/varun/</guid><description>Varun Arunachalam Chandran, PhD
Postdoctoral Research Associate- Faculty of biology, medicine and health, University of Manchester
Email: varun.chandran@manchester.ac.uk
Currently, I work as a postdoctoral research associate for a study titled ‘Neuroimaging in Rasopathies’ (funded by NIHR-BRC) at the faculty of biology, medicine and health, University of Manchester, United Kingdom. In the current research project, we examine the inhibitory/excitatory imbalance associated with GABA/glutamate, functional connectivity and myelin differences underpinning learning and working memory difficulties in children with Rasopathies specifically including Neurofibromatosis type-I and Noonan Syndrome as well as its phenotypic relationship with Autism Spectrum Conditions (ASC).</description></item></channel></rss>